Guide to the Peter Štanský Papers SC0190
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Peter Štanský papers
1930s-2015
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Štanský, Peter
SC0190
34.75 Linear Feet (31 boxes)
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of Peter Štanský, 1983-2016.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Peter Štanský, born in New York in 1932, has had a long and distinguished career in the field of history. He received his first BA in History from Yale, and a few years later received his second BA in History from King’s College, Cambridge. Assuming he would eventually go into the practice of Law, he sent out but then withdrew applications to Harvard Law School, eventually earning his Ph.D. in History from Harvard. He taught at Harvard until 1968, when he joined the Stanford faculty. In 1974 Štanský became the holder of the endowed Frances and Charles Field Chair in History, and has been the chairman of Stanford's History Department for at least two terms.
Stanksy’s scholarly interests have been quite diverse during his time at Stanford University. He has authored or co-authored numerous books on British social and literary topics, such as The Unknown Orwell, The Road to Wigan Pier, Orwell: The Transformation, Ambitions and Strategies, and numerous other books on subjects including Winston Churchill, Victorian society, William Morris, and William Gladstone. Along with scholarly publications, Štanský has served on many Stanford committees and has been actively involved with the Stanford University Library collection development.
Description of the Collection
The first series of the Peter Štanský papers consists of three different sections, each representing a distinct academic activity Peter Štanský was involved with: his committee involvement, his publishing activities, and his library correspondence. His committee work ranged from Academic Senate, the Drama Department, the English Department, the Land and Building Committee, and the Foreign Campus Sub-Committee which was centered in Cliveden, England. The content of this section is predominantly minutes and correspondence with various committee members. The last of these committees, the Foreign Campus Sub-Committee, contains both the minutes of the meetings (boxes 2 and 3) and class lists and syllabi (box 4). Peter Štanský’s publishing activities constitute the second major portion of this collection. Along with the actual material dealing with the compilation of the text or book, this section also includes correspondence with the various publishers, such as Harcourt and Garland. The last two boxes of this collection (boxes 10 and 11) contain file cards with notes on his various publications. Finally, Peter Štanský was involved with Stanford’s library development, and included in his papers are his correspondence with the Stanford University Libraries from 1968-1980 (box 9).
An addition made in 2003 consists of two scrapbooks on Štanský's career, 1960-69. Accession 2015-167 contains materials from Štanský's early education, family letters, and research about Marina Alandra Vaizey. Accession 2017-060 contains research files for Štanský's book Edward Upward: Art and Life.
England -- Intellectual life -- Study and teaching.; Great Britain -- Politics and government -- Study and teaching.; Štanský, Peter; Stanford University. Overseas Study Program; Štanský, Peter; Stanford University. Department of History; Stanford University. Libraries; Stanford University. Senate of the Academic Council
- Papers
  - Academic Senate, 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Academic Senate, 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Academic Senate, 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Academic Senate, 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Academic Senate, 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Academic Senate, 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Academic Senate, 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Academic Senate, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Academic Senate, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Academic Senate, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Committee on Drama Department, 1975-1981 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Visiting Scholars Committee, 1968-1970 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Visiting Scholars Committee, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Land and Building Committee, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Land and Building Committee, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Land and Building Committee, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - SGES Committee on English, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Foreign Campus Sub-Committee, Britain, 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Foreign Campus Sub-Committee, Britain, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Foreign Campus Sub-Committee, Britain, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Foreign Campus Sub-Committee, Britain, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Foreign Campus Sub-Committee, Britain, 1970-1972 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Foreign Campus Sub-Committee, Britain, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Foreign Campus Sub-Committee, Britain, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Foreign Campus Sub-Committee, Britain, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Clivedon Sub-Committee, Britain, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Clivedon Sub-Committee, Britain, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Clivedon Sub-Committee, Britain, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Clivedon Sub-Committee, Britain, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Clivedon Sub-Committee, Britain, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Clivedon Sub-Committee, Britain, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Clivedon Sub-Committee, Britain, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Foreign Campus Sub-Committee, Britain (class lists and syllabi), 1971 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Foreign Campus Sub-Committee, Britain (class lists and syllabi), 1971 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Clivedon Sub-Committee, Britain (class lists and syllabi), 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Clivedon Sub-Committee, Britain (class lists and syllabi), 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Stanford in Britain (class lists and syllabi), 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Save Clivedon Committee 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Publications: England Since 1867, chapters 1-2 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Publications: England Since 1867, chapters 3-4 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Publications: England Since 1867, chapters 5 - (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Publications: England, a textbook (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Publications: England, a textbook, continued (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Publications: England, a textbook, continued (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Publications: England, a textbook, continued (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Publications: England, a textbook, continued (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Publications: England, a textbook, continued (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Publications: On Nineteen Eighty-Four (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Publications: On Nineteen Eighty-Four (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Publications: On Nineteen Eighty-Four (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Publishing activities: Defoe (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Publishing activities: Victorian Studies, 1964-1969 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Publishing activities: Victorian Studies, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Publishing activities: Victorian Studies, 1970-1973 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Publishing activities: Victorian Essays (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Publishing activities: Victorian Essays (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Publishing activities: Churchill (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Publishing activities: Churchill (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Publishing activities: Harcourt, 1966-1971 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Publishing activities: Harcourt, 1966-1971 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Publishing activities: Harcourt, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Publishing activities: Harcourt, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Publishing activities: Harcourt, 1973 - (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Publishing activities: Harcourt, 1973 - (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Publishing activities: Harvester Press Ltd. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Publishing activities: W. M. Conway Essay (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Publishing activities: W. M. Conway Essay (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Publishing activities: Garland Publishing (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Publishing activities: Garland Publishing (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Publishing activities: Garland Publishing (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Publishing activities: Garland Publishing (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Publishing activities: Garland Publishing (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Publishing activities: Lyttleton and Thring (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Publishing activities: Lyttleton and Thring (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Publishing activities: Morley’s Historical Review (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Publishing activities: Morley’s Historical Review (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Publishing activities: British Labour (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Publishing activities: British Labour (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Publishing activities: British Labour (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Stanford University Libraries, 1968-1971 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Stanford University Libraries, 1972-1980 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Stanford University Libraries, 1973-1974 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Notes on publications (note cards) (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - File cards with notes on publications (Box 10)
  - File cards with notes on publications (Box 11)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2003-096
  - Two scrapbooks on Štanský's career (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Volume 1, 1960-1966, with clippings, reprints, magazines, programs, and 1 photograph 1; Volume 2, 1966-69, with clippings, newsletters, reprints, and 1 photograph
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2009-183
  - National Book Awards, thru 1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - British Politics Group (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - National Book Club Stationary, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American Historical Association Correspondence, 1970-1980? (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - National Book Awards, 1974 on (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Australian Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Historical Association Correspondence, 1971-1976 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Historical Association Correspondence, 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Canada Council, 1978-1983 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Fulbright/CIES, 1983-1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - CVIS Project, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Library--Current Correspondence, 1975-1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Humanities and International Relations Applications, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Modern Thouth and Literature Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Oxford Panel correspondence, 1986-1989 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Periodicals, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - General correspondence?, 1969-1986 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Pulizter Biography Jury Correspondence, 1985, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Promotions, 1970s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Radical Biographies, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Readings for Articles, 1968-1975 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Visiting Scholars, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Thorne, Robert, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Toohey, Timothy, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Takahiro, Ueyama, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Tuffield, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Vicinus, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Waters, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - S. Weaver, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Phillip Wainwright, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Linda Walker, 1978-79 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Weiler, Peter, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - D. Wessner, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Wiener, Martin, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Willis, Richard and Kirk, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Winton, Hall, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Wolf, L., 1989 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Zast, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Zimmerman, K., 1997 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Zimmerman, T.C. Price, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Reading--Stanford, 1961-1973 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Appointments and Promotions (department), 1986 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Victorian Studies, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Ralph Fox and the Revolutionary Novel, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - The Bourgeois Dilemma in England, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - MSS-Permissions, etc., 1960-1963 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Thesis Card Indexes (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Old Thesis Correspondence and Sources, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - MISC, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Outside Talks, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Vienna, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Oxford/WM, 1982-1987 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Horne, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Publishers/William Morris, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - William Morris - Course, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Morris--Hoover Library, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - William Morris Exhibit-Other Events Lectures-Activities-Miscellaneous, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Morris, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - William Morris Society-Miscellany and other Correspondence, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Norman Kelvin Correspondence WM. Morris Lectures Other, 1977-1980 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Morris--Miscellaneous, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Princeton II, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Morris--Lectures Books, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Princeton I, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - SPOSS, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Garland, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Garland/New Series, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Garland, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Bookstore, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Various Papers - Rhodes Scholarship, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Career, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Course, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - History 103/ Humanities, 1992-93 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Course--144B, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Course--144B, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - New History Course, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - San Diego, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Royal Society, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Course--144B, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Graduate Colloq., 1970-72 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Vict. Prose, 1981-82 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - International Relations - Humanities, 1976-77 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Graduate Colloq., 1968-69 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Course 143, 1984-85 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Seminar, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - History 144, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Course 144, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Hist 145 Spring, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - History 145, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Course--144B, 1983-84 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Hist 41, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Course--Exams, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - SHC Advisory Board, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Course, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - SUP, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Rhodes, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - PBK, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Yale, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - NYU, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Library, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Library, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - HIV, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Essays, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Duke, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - JBS, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - DMB, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Jobs, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Dangerfield, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Štanský, Peter - Statistics, August 1990 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Peter Štanský CHH, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Briggs, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Berlin, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - AA, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - AHR, 1991-1993 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Stanford Centre in Oxford, 2001-2002 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - History 145 100B, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Hoover, 1969, 1972, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Rhodes Scholarship, 1969-1972 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Book Lists, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Freshmen, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Papers, Essays, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - History 144, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - H L Part (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Missouri, University of, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Hist Lit, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - History Dept., 1969 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Kirkland, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - SocSci 15 - Past Meetings (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Books, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Soc Sci 3 Spring, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Misc, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - AHA - Štanský, 1961-1965 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Travel/Bills, 1962-1968 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - McKenzie, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Jews, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Travel, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Social Sciences, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Tests/Reading Lists, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Friedman, Leslie, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Guth, Gloria, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Hansen, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Harris, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Susan Hinely, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Hollinder, David, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Horowitz, Dan, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Howard, Michael, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Hume, Leslie, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Hymans, Herbert, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Jarrett, Mark, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Jaffee, Brita, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Kesner, Richard (vol. 1), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Kesner, Richard (2nd Vol) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Rudeny Koekme, Fall 1980 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Koven, 1993-2002 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Kuhol, 1989-1997 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Charles Kimball, 1985-1990 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Slavia/Kosru/Koencke, 1993-1995 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Lesser, W, 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Lyman, Richard, 1960-1991 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Chip Long, 1980-1989 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Lavva Marshall, 1989-1995 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Marsh, Peter, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Martin, 1990-2000 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Malcolm, Howard, 1973-1990 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Macdonald, Michael, 1973-1980 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Mann, Kristin, 1971-1975 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Mellini, Peter, 1980-1990 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Newman, Geral, 1969-1987 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Orsmeth, 1990-1998 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Osborne, John, 1970-1980 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Otto, Patricia, 1970-2001 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Padgett, Nancy, 1972-1974 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Deuwick, 1987-1991 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Phillips, Bradely, 1974-1980 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Phillips, Gregory, 1976-1980 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Doirien, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Richardson, 2003-2008 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Riddell, Norman, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Amy Robinson, 1991-200 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Robinson, Paul (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Recommendations: Misc "A" (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Recommendations: Misc "B" (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Recommendations Misc "C" (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Recommendations Misc "D" (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Recommendations Misc "E" (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Recommendations Misc "F" (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Recommendations Misc "G" (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Recommendations Misc "H" (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Recommendations Misc "I" (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Recommendations Misc "J" (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Recommendations Misc "K" (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Recommendations Misc "L" (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Recommendations Misc "M" (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Recommendations Misc "N" (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Recommendations Misc "O" (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Recommendations Misc "P" (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Recommendations Misc "Q" (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Recommendations Misc "R'" (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Recommendations Misc "S" (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Recommendations Misc "T" (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Recommendations Misc "U" (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Recommendations Misc "V" (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Recommendations Misc "W" (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Recommendations Misc "X-Y-Z (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Martin Anderson, 1995-2000 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Ayer, Douglas, 1985-1988 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Bailkin, 1993-1995 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Bailkin, 1983-1990 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Bailkin, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Bailkin, 1975-1979 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Bailkin, 1973-2007 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Bernstein, Henry, 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - John Brioch, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Ben-Amos, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - L. Bisceglia, 1983-1990 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Bronstein, 1987-1992 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Britain, 1981-1986 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Butler, Jeffrey, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Callahan, Ray, 1968-1984 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Cargill, T, 1979-1996 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Chandler, 1982-1988 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Cline, Peter, 1967-1976 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Curtis, 1972-1990 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Clive, John, 1974-1988 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Conklin, Gary, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Crowl, David, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Dunkley, Peter, 1975-1992 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Foster, Frank, 1973-1981 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Arion Press (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - University of Chicago, 1979-1983 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Card index: Orwell (Box 15)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2014-007
  Scope and Contents
  The Peter Štanský subject files include manuscripts, research, correspondence, and reviews of some of Štanský’s publications dated 1974-2010. Subjects covered include C.R. Ashbee and H.W. Rolfe, Julian Bell, the Blitz, Bloomsbury, twentieth-century British artists, William Gladstone, William Morris, George Orwell, and Philip and Sybil Sassoon.
  British history -- 20th century; British literature -- 20th century.; Štanský, Peter
  - Ashbee/Rolfe subject files, 1974-1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Julian Bell subject files, 1966-2007
    This subject file contains research and correspondence about Julian Bell (1908-1937), an English poet and nephew of Virginia Woolf. Peter Štanský published two books about Julian Bell, including Journey to the Frontier: Julian Bell and John Cornford: Their lives and the 1930s with William Abrahams (1966), and Julian Bell: From Bloomsbury to the Spanish Civil War (2012).
    - Research, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1982-2007 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Journey to the Frontier illustrations, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Blitz subject files, 2006-2010
    This subject file contains manuscripts and correspondence about the Blitz in London (1940-1941). It also contains book reviews for Peter Štanský’s publication The First Day of the Blitz (2007).
    - Manuscripts, 2006-2010 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - The First Day of the Blitz book reviews, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - The First Day of the Blitz illustrations, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - London's Burning, interview on KPFA, 1994 Oct 28; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Bloomsbury subject files, 1986-1998
    This subject file contains manuscripts about Bloomsbury, as well as correspondence and book reviews for Peter Štanský’s publication On or About 1910: Early Bloomsbury and its Intimate World (1996).
    - Manuscripts, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1986-1998 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - On or About December 1910: Early Bloomsbury and its Intimate World book reviews, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Illustrations, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - British artist subject files, undated (Box 1, Item 13-14)
    This subject file contains handwritten and typed notecards by Peter Štanský about twentieth-century British artists such as Henry Moore (1898-1986), Graham Sutherland (1903-1980), Paul Nash (1889-1946), and Benjamin Britten (1913-1976).
  - William Gladstone subject files, 1978-1979
    In 1979 Peter Štanský’s book about the British politician William Ewart Gladstone (1809-1898) called Gladstone: A Progress in Politics was published. This subject file includes a manuscript of the book, as well as correspondence and book reviews related to the publication.
    - Gladstone: A Progress in Politics manuscript, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Gladstone: A Progress in Politics book reviews, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - William Morris subject files, 1985-2006
    Peter Štanský researched and wrote two books about William Morris (1834-1896), an English artist and writer associated with the Arts and Crafts Movement. The book William Morris was published in 1983 and From William Morris to Sergeant Pepper in 1999. This research file contains some of Štanský’s manuscripts about Morris, along with correspondence and book reviews of From William Morris to Sergeant Pepper.
    - Manuscripts (1 of 2), undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Manuscripts (2 of 2), undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, 1985-2006 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - From William Morris to Sergeant Pepper book reviews, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - George Orwell subject files, 1953-2005